A Guide to the Reginald M. Archibald papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA146
Rockefeller Archive Center
Reginald M. Archibald papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1930-1982
Rockefeller Archive Center
Archibald, Reginald M.
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA146
7.48 Cubic Feet 17 boxes.
17 boxes.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 Ar25
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for scholarly research.
Chemistry; Biochemistry; Biology -- Research; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Electrophoresis; Medicine, Preventive; Medical research; Archibald, Reginald M.; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University
- Biographical materials, bibliographies, 1930-1976
  - R.M. Archibald. "Work of Dr. R.M. Archibald and his group", 1955 October 19; 3 pp typescript (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - News from The Rockefeller University. "Biography of R.M. Archibald", 1973 September (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Survey of Sources for the History of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes: Biographical and professional information and Archibald bibliography 1930-1976. [Handwritten numbers, corrections and additions by Ruth Sternfeld.] Photocopy.
  - Exchange with Laurenda Daniells, University Archivist, University of British Columbia [re] E.H. Archibald (R.M. Archibald's father) and R.M. Archibald's recollections of childhood connections with the University of British Columbia. Photocopies, 1985 November 5 1985 December 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography, 1930-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - R.M. Archibald 1941?, 1952, 1963 Convocation
    - R.M. Archibald laboratory interiors in 1949, Founder's Hall, Room 413
  - Personal correspondence, 1943-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Arrangement note
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - L.G. Bowen, NRC/R.M. Archibald exchange [re] R.M. Archibald reprints on investigative work during NRC fellowship, 1943 October 30-1946 November 25
    - Exchange with T.M. Rivers, 1946 October 25-1949 December 19
      [re] Descriptions of investigations by Dr. Archibald. Laboratory space and apparatus requirements for setting up the Archibald laboratory at RIMR.
      Staff requirements and appointments.
      D.D. Van Slyke equipment to R.M. Archibald.
    - S.T. Baur? /Archibald [re] Baur's reprint, Nature letter on the "Crystallization of Arginase", 1947 April 2
    - A.R. Dochez/Archibald. Letter of appointment as Physician to RIMR Hospital, effective 1948 January 26, 1948 July 1
    - D.D. Van Slyke/Archibald. [re] laboratory helper and preparations, 1948 May 3
    - Archibald/A.J. Campo. [re] Van Slyke equipment to Archibald, 1950 September 8 1950 September 15
    - Archibald/Nobelkommittén. [re] D.D. Van Slyke. Includes excerpt from Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism editorial on development of better quantitative methods for clinical chemists, (carbon copy), 1953 December 16
    - Charles Best/Archibald. Invitation as visiting lecturer to School of Graduate Studies, University of Toronto, 1958 November 17
    - Archibald/Charles H. Best. Declines invitation and recommends Drs. Ahrens, Rasmussen, Klebanoff and Dziewatkowski, 1958 December 2
    - J. Campbell/Archibald, [re] Archibald letter to C. Best, 1958 December 23
  - Johns Hopkins University, School of Hygiene and Public Health, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Biographical/Historical note
    R.M. Archibald, Professor of Biochemistry during this period.
    Correspondence deals with staff requirements and appointments, biochemistry courses and textbooks, various expenses and students.
    Special interest item: 1948 January 26. Archibald/Dr. Stebbins, Director, School of Hygiene and Public Health, Johns Hopkins University Letter of resignation as of June 30, 1948 to membership in RI Hospital.
  - Johns Hopkins University, School of Hygiene and Public Health. Nutrition Foundation, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Correspondence deals with grants-in-aid made by Millbank Foundation and Nutrition Foundation to help support project on "influence of Hormones on Activity of Enzymes and on Bone Formation" at Johns Hopkins University, School of Hygiene and Public Health. Includes plans and schedules for Eastern District study of underweight and overweight children in white public schools.
- RU Administration 1943, 1960, 1967-1969, and Hospital Vacation Schedules 1961-1964, 1943-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Special interest item:
  - exchange w/E.B. Smith [re] Levene chemical collection, 1943 February-March
  - exchange w/Robert Loeb [re] Robert Slater, 1967 April
  - [re] Lucia Saccone, 1968 February 9
  - re Nicola Di Ferrante ms "The Differential Diagnosis of Postpuberal Virilism", [undated]
    Includes typescript of ms.
- Isotope Committee, 1948-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Original committee appointed by Dr. Gasser: R.M. Archibald. Chairman, D.D. Dziewiatkowski, T. Shedlovsky, F.L. Horsfall.
  Correspondence, rules and regulations and changes.
  Includes some correspondence with Marguerite V. Patmore, Frank Horsfall, W. Flinn as to those who work with organic solvents (benzine). Also includes Atomic Energy Commission regulations/amendments 1957-1969 with 2 reprints.
- Reports on USPHS grants, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  R.M. Archibald, principal investigator, Grant #'s A-2772, A-3347, AM08216, AM02772.
- Applications for staff appointments to RU, 1961-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Deuel, Thomas F., 1969
  - Ganguly, A. [Originally Gangopadhyaya], 1969-1974
  - Goodfriend, T., 1961-1964
  - Kang, H.-C., 1969-1970
  - Katz, S.H., 1966-1967
  - Lin, Fang-Jin, 1963-1965
  - Merker, Edward, 1969
  - Samii, A.H., 1964
  - Stoller, James, 1973
- Correspondence, 1943-1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Cyanamid and Chemical Corp 1943. [re] Keralin enzyme concentrate H & K.
  - American Institute of Chemists 1948. [re] Archibald membership in. Encl: AIC leaflet
  - Carpenter, Rowena S. 1946 [re] education films on nutrition
  - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists [Signed by A. Einstein], 1948
    Encl: Statement and A. Einstein "Atomic War or Peace" Atlantic Monthly reprint.
  - Howard, John E. [re] ms, 1948
  - Schwarz Laboratories [re] Polidase-S, 1943-1944
  - Wallerstein Laboratories [re] Mylase P. and Reductone, 1944-1945
    Includes graphs on Arginase.
- Grant Records, 1964 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  R.M. Archibald, Principal Investigator.
  PHS Grant #'s: AMO3347-06, AMO3347-09, DE-176-03, NB-06895-02, NB-06895-03 and 03SI.
- Budgets, 1948-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  R.M. Archibald laboratory, isotope and spectroscopic laboratory budgets. Includes correspondence re equipment, etc. for isotope and spectroscopic laboratories.
- Budgets, 1961-1967 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  R.M. Archibald laboratory and isotope laboratory budgets.
- American Association of Clinical Chemists. Van Slyke Award, 1957-1958; 5" Hollinger (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Dr. Archibald member of Van Slyke award nominating committee in 1957 and 1958.
- American Board of Clinical Chemists, 1957-1962 1963 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Board is analogous to various medical specialty boards and organized under sponsorship of ACS, ASBC, AIC, AACC.
  Dr. Archibald elected to Board in 1958 and served as Vice-President 1959-1963?
  File consists of minutes of meetings, resolutions and correspondence as Board develops and determines role. Correspondents, include: Kurt Dubowski, W.A. Wolff, Robert M. Hill, Joseph I. Routh among others.
- American Board of Pathology, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Dr. Archibald serves as a consultant for the Board.
  Deals with Board exams in Clinical Chemistry, standardization of cyanmethemoglobin. Includes set of questions and Dr. Archibald's editing of. Also includes reprint from The Modern Hospital, February 1967, "Why Laboratory Standards Are Substandard". Correspondence primarily with Douglas A. MacFadyen, but includes Bradley E. Copeland and Edward B. Smith.
- American Society of Biological Chemists (ASBC), 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Dr. Archibald member of Committee on Clinical Chemistry of ASBC [re] training of clinical chemists.
  Consists primarily of drafts of proposals, reports and correspondence with members of Committee on Clinical Chemistry (Robert M. Hill, Wm. J. Darby, M.F. Mason, A.J. Quick) and with members of American Board of Clinical Chemistry. This group cooperated with the AMA Joint Committee to study Paramedical Areas in Relation to Medicine (Dr. R.M. McKeown, Chairman).
- American Society of Biological Chemists. E.V. McCollum Award Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Dr. Archibald member of McCollum Award Committee.
  E.V. McCollum award presented 1959 April 14, Atlantic City, NJ.
- Analytical Chemistry, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Term Dr. Archibald serves on advisory board of publication.
  Related correspondence primarily with L.T. Hallett, Editor.
- Correspondence, 1942-1969 (primarily 1940s); 3 folders
  - A-Ho (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Animal Welfare Institute, 1951
    - Barrett, G. Clifford [re] specialty chemicals, 1969
    - Bauer, Walter. Helen Hay Whitney Foundation interest in work on connective tissues, 1960
    - Bauer, Göran. H., 1968
    - Beckman, WM. W. Professional colleagues and friends, 1942-1944
    - Bloom, M.D. Comments on endocrine findings in paper by Keutel on Bloom syndrome patients, 1968
    - Blythe, Wm. B. [re] Martin Rizack, 1968
    - Chaney, Albert L. [re] method for barbituate determination, 1945
    - Cori, Gerty T., 1951
    - Cournand, Andre, 1943
    - Despopoulus, Agamemnon, 1944
    - Everett, M.R. [re] - reference on allontoin, 1944
    - Futcher, P.H., 1943
    - Gentzkow, C.J., 1942
    - Gonzales, T.A. [re] D.D. Van Slyke request of Medical Examiner's office for blood of patients dying of cyanide poisoning, 1946
    - Green, H.N., 1943
    - Hamilton, P.B. RIMR colleagues on various laboratory results, 1943-1944
    - Herrold, E.A., 1944
    - Hitchcock, P. Interest in Dr. Archibald's work on barbituates, 1945
    - Houck, R. On questioned difference between muscle adenosine and yeast adenosine, 1943
    - Howe, H.E. Explanation for submission of ms to Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, 1943
  - Hunter, Andrew, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Correspondence between professional colleagues.
  - K-W (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Klemperer, F. [re] uricase, 1944
    - Lauson, H., 1944
    - [re] Lewis, U.J., 1968
    - Lichtenstein, N. [re] glutamine, 1942
    - Luschinsky, H., 1950
    - MacFadyen, D.A. [re] orthophenanthrolene-ferrous complex, 1943
    - Manske, R.H. [re] quinolines and cyanide dyes, 1944
    - Morley, Mrs., 1943
    - Opie, E.L. [re] use of autopsied human kidney, 1942-1943
    - Pereyra, A.J., 1944
      Includes copy of portion of Archibald ms on the nature of the reaction between proteins and anionic detergents.
    - Richards, D.W. [re] blood with unknown organic acid present, 1943
    - Rosen, D.N., 1943-1944
    - Russell, J.A., 1943-1944; (carbon copy)
      Includes ms "Colorimetric Determination of Ammonia by the Phenolate-Hypochloride Reaction"
    - Sayers, G. [re] modification of uric acid method, 1944
    - Schlenk, F. Exchange [re] testing of codehydrogenase I and nicotinamide nucleoside, 1943
    - Schmierer, Irving L. [re] suggestions of lecturers from RI, 1967
    - Society for Adolescent Medicine, 1969
    - Stander, H.J. [re] analysis of human milk, 1946
    - Straus, O.H., 1943
    - Sunderman, F.W., 1943
    - Van Slyke, D.D. [re] mss for publication, 1943
    - Vickery, H.B. [re] preparation of glutamine, 1943
    - Waverly Press. Request for diagram of apparatus, 1943
    - Williams, Carroll [re] method for determination of thiouracil in blood, 1945
- International Congress of Clinical Chemistry, New York City, Hotel Barbizon-Plaza, 1956 September 9-14 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Dr. Archibald serves on Committee for Scientific Program, Chairman of Session I and a delegate from NAS/NRC.
  Includes correspondence, program, abstracts of papers in Clinical Chemistry v. 2 (August 1956). Also includes copy of report to NAS/NRC from delegates to Congress, copies of 3 papers and "A Brief Description of the International Council of Scientific Unions (ICSU) 1956 prepared by NAS-NRC Office of International Relations.
- Journal of Biological Chemistry (JBC), 1947-1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Dr. Archibald member of Editorial Board of JBC December 1947-June 1958.
  Correspondence among editorial staff dealing with procedures, style, costs, appointment of new or additional editors and minutes of meetings.
  Correspondents: R.J. Anderson, Warren M. Sperry, D. Wright Wilson, Philip Handler.
  Some items of special interest are suggested changes for preparation of mss; 1952 April 2 letter from A.N. Richards recalling JBC early history and financial support by Christian Herter.
  [See also: Box (4) Folder 4].
- Journal of Biological Chemistry Reports on Operations, 1948-1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Includes copy of report to the Council of the American Society of Biological Chemistry on Journal's financial structure as requested at 1953 Spring meeting.
- Journal of Biological Chemistry, 1948-1957 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Record by editor of mss received and disposition; i.e. "Accepted", "rejected", "accepted with revision".
- Journal of Biological Chemistry, 1948-1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Special Correspondence between Editors.
  Letters dealing with mss which have required additional opinions from various editors.
- Editorial decision letters on mss submitted for publication in JBC. Pages in each folder numbered consecutively to maintain order.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - A-L (#1-209), 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - M-W (#210-424), 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - (#1-200), 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - (#0-113), 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - (#2-111), 1952 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - (#0-106), 1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - (#1-132), 1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - (#1-90), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Editorial decision letters, 1956; 2½" Hollinger (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Editorial decision letters, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Editorial decision letters, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Journal of Biological Chemistry (JBC), 1948-1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Correspondence among editorial staff dealing with procedures, style, costs, appointments of new or additional editors, minutes of editorial meetings and nomenclature.
  Correspondents: R.J. Anderson, H.B. Vickery, Philip Handler, John T. Edsall, Wm. H. Stein.
  Special interest items:
  - Exchange re Herter Memorial Fund, 1954 May 18 1954 May 20 1954 August 6
  - Report of JBC Committee on Abbreviation. Fifth draft, 1958 April
  - List (photocopied) of members of JBC editorial board who served with Dr. Anderson during his term of managing editor 1937-1958, 1958 November 12
  - William H. Stein/Archibald. Letter of appreciation for service on JBC editorial board, 1958 June 16
- Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism, 1952-1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Dr. Archibald member of editorial board 1953-1960.
  Correspondence among editorial staff dealing with procedure, style, costs, appointments of new or additional members, mss reviews by Archibald and others, and meetings.
  Special items of interest:
  - Report of managing editor of JCEM, 1952
  - Rawson, R.W. /Archibald. Thank you for service on editorial board of JCEM, 1960 July
- Science, 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Mss reviews by Dr. Archibald for publication in Science.
- Correspondence, 1940-1946 1954; 5" Hollinger
  Primarily re sample requests, purchase of chemicals and requesting information for investigative work. In 4 folders:
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    re aldehyde resins with Philips Petroleum Co., Quaker Oats, Borden Co., Durez Co., DuPont
  - Correspondence A-Ho (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - American Cyanimide and Chemical Co., 1943
    - American Resinous Chemicals Corp., 1944
    - Amino Products Co., 1943
    - Anachemia Ltd., 1944
    - Armstrong, A.R., 1943
    - Atlas Powder Co., 1945-1946
    - Becco Sales Corp., 1943-1944
    - Bergmann, 1944
    - Bergstrom, F.W., 1944
    - Buffalo Electrochemical Co., 1943
    - Calgon, Inc., 1944
    - Carbide and Carbon Chemicals Corp., 1944
    - Corcoran, A.C. (Lilly Lab), 1942
    - Darco Corp., 1944
    - Darrow, D.C., 1943
    - Dicalcite Co., 1944
    - DuPont de Nemours, E.I. and Co., 1943-1944
    - Eastman Kodak Co., 1943
    - Edwal Laboratories, 1944
    - Emulsol Corp., 1943-1944
    - General Foods Corp., 1944
    - Gwaudan-Delawanna Inc., 1944
    - Great Western Sugar Co., 1942
    - Greeff, R.W. & Co., 1944
    - Hooker Electrochemical Co., 1944
  - Correspondence Hynson-Sh (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Hynson, Westcott & Dunning, 1944
    - Johns-Manville, 1943
    - Kalkar, H., 1943
    - Koppers Co., 1944
    - Lehn & Fink, 1943
    - Lilly Research Laboratories, 1944
    - Martin Laboratories, 1944
    - Mead Johnson & Co., 1943
    - Merck & Co., 1943-1945
    - Monsanto Chemical Co., 1943-1944
    - National Sugar Refining Co., 1942
    - Naugatuck Chemical, 1944
    - New Jersey Zinc Co., 1944
    - Ohio Chemical and Mfg. Co., 1944
    - Parke Davis Co., 1942 1944
    - Roblin, R.O., 1945
    - S.M.A. Corp., 1942
    - Schuykill Chemical Co., 1944
    - Shedlovsky, L., 1943
  - Correspondence Squibb-Winthrop (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Squibb, E.R. & Sons, 1942
    - Squibb Institute for Medical Research, 1943-1944
    - Terhout, W.P., 1943
    - Todd Scientific Glass Apparatus Co., 1944
    - Tretolite Co., 1944
    - Union Bay State Co., 1943-1944
    - United States Rubber Co., 1944
    - Victor Chemical Works, 1943-1944
    - Vincent, George Inc., 1944
    - Wallace & Tieran Products, 1943-1944
    - Wellcome Research Laboratories, 1944
    - Wellington Sears Co., 1944
    - Wilson, D.W., 1944
    - Winthrop Chemical Co., 1944
    - Winthrop-Stearns, 1949
      Includes 1949 February 16, "Preparation of Testosterone Ethymercaptoacetate"
- Equipment, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Technicon Fraction Collector
    Includes correspondence with E.C. Weiskopf, Jr. of Technicon re problems with and use of Fraction Collector, photographs of and "Instructions for Fraction Collector," and "Directions for Regrinding Counter Current Extraction Apparatus".
- Laboratory notes
  Hand numbered consecutively as found.
  - Miscellaneous procedures., 1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Scope and Contents
    Handwritten, many worked out by D.D. Van Slyke. pp 1-75.
  - Clinical laboratory notes, 1943-1945 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Including procedures and protocols of things to be tried.
    Urease standardization, colorimetric serum calcium, blood sugar alcohol determination, determination of sulphur drugs. Standardization of phenol, plasma albumin specific gravity, protocols for experiments on use of ninhydrin. pp 1-113.
  - Calibration - Room 712, 1941-1946; pp 0-66 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Blood sugar
    - Pipette calibration, 1942
    - Calibration of glass machine chamber, 1942
    - 25cc Burette Exax, 1941
    - Calibrations 10cc pipette with water, 1942
    - Calibration of weights, 1945
    - Calibration of TT for use in cuvette, 1946
  - Literature notes: Barbituric acid, pp 0-40 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Literature notes: Enzyme kinetics, pp 0-141 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Literature notes: Glutamine, pp 1-120 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Arginase kinetics I, 1940 October-1941 February; 5" Hollinger pp 1-167 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Original indexing at beginning of folder.
  - Arginase II, 1941 February-April; pp 1-182 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Arginase II, 1941 June-1942 June; pp 1-165 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Studies of human hepatic arginase, 1941 February-1942 January; pp 1-21 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Kidney glutaminase, 1942 February-September; pp 1-140 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Arginase analysis (hydrolysates), 1942 June 1942 November-December; pp 0-40 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Includes typescript of Van Slyke and Archibald, "Enzymatic Manometric Determination of Arginine".
  - Arginase paper by Van Slyke and Archibald, "The Manometric Determination of Arginine by Use of Activated Arginase" (Folder 1), 1942; pp 1-138
    Included in folder:
    - General plan of paper on arginase (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Some Properties of Hepatic Arginase", 3 copies of paper (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1st copy on kinetic arginase (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Directors Report: Archibald and Shedlovsky on urine proteins, 1942 March (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Chemical Journal Club report (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Hospital Rounds Report (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - RI Staff meeting, R.M. Archibald, "Some Properties of Hepatic Arginase", 1942 May 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Announcement of meeting and handwritten copy of paper, pp 1-27 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Laboratory records. Products Catalogs, 5" Hollinger (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory notes and records
    - Colorimetric Canavanine with some notes on literature, 1942 December-1943 December 1945 August-1946 June; pp 1-131 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Colorimetric Urea, 1944 January-1945 August; pp 1-134 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Thiouracil March 1945, Colorimetric arginase March 1945-May 1946, 1945 March-1946 May; pp 1-62 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Colorimetric cyanide with some notes on literature, 1945 November-1946 March; pp 1-83 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Creatimines, 1943 January-June (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Protein hydrolystates, 1946 January-May; pp 0-35 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Uric Acid, 1942 August-1943 December; pp 0-86 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Includes literature notes and copy of write-up on Plasmic Uric Acid for Army manual
    - Urease, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Includes literature notes and methods.
      - "Manometric Urease Method of Determining Urea in Whole Blood...", 3 pp typescript. pp 1-47.
    - Mycology, 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Consists of correspondence with Dr. Frederick Reiss, Dermatological Clinic, New York Hospital, re chemical testing on patient including some experimental work on mycology. Includes literature notes.
    - Glutaminase II, 1942 September-1943 January; 5" Hollinger pp 1-135 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Glutaminase III, 1943 January-February; pp 0-92 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Glutaminase IV, 1943 March-November; pp 1-159 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Glutaminase V, 1943 November-1944 September; pp 1-155 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Includes notes on antifoam December 1943-January 1944.
    - Dog Shock, 1943 June-October; pp 1-45 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Experiments with glutamate and adenosine.
      Includes 2 June 1943. Effect of adenosine and glutamate on dog under nembutal. Effect of glycine saline and glutamate after hemorrhage and trauma, (readings).
      Notes taken after visit with Dr. Cournand.
    - Dog Shock, 1943 November; 2 pp typescript. pp 1-31 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Dogs in various degrees of hemorrhage shock.
      Includes "As a part of a study of the temporary and permanent effects of severe shock on enzyme systems of liver and kidney..."
    - Milk glutamine 1945 and Lipase 1946, 1945-1946; pp 1-45 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Laboratory notes, 1946-1947; pp 0-162 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Readings of various phases of treated or untreated urines.
    - Alloxen gasometric determination, 1944 April-1945 February; 5" Hollinger pp 1-144 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Alloxan gasometric literature notes, pp 1-73 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Laboratory procedures and preparations, pp 0-65 (Box 9, Folder 3)